## chris tsongas

cell 503-709-6445 • email chris.tsongas@gmail.com • postal mail 500 westover dr #5221 • sanford, nc • 27330

**PROFILE** 

Chris Tsongas has an extraordinary talent for turning complex processes into simple and intuitive user experiences. He is fanatical about using responsive design to create websites that look beautiful and are easy to use on any device. In addition to teaching web development, Chris is a certified yoga and AcroYoga instructor.

Proficient in HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Redux, Node, Ruby on Rails, SQL, MongoDB and Git.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Full-Stack JavaScript Bootcamp Mentor, Thinkful, Educational Startup NEW YORK, NEW YORK - 2014 - CURRENT

Mentor students in the use of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, including React, Redux, and Node.

JavaScript Immersion Instructor, Portland Code School, Educational Startup PORTLAND, OREGON - 2015

Taught full-stack JavaScript development including Node, Express, Heroku, Redis, and MongoDB.

Computer Science & Web Development Instructor, Code Fellows, Educational Startup PORTLAND, OREGON - 2014 - 2015

Taught HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and fundamentals of Computer Science in the classroom.

Front End Web Engineer, G5, Search Marketing Agency BEND, OREGON - 2013 - 2014

 Projects included using a combination of Ruby on Rails, HTML, SASS, JavaScript and multiple jQuery plugins to create a responsive image gallery partial with lightbox that loads the smallest images needed for each device.

Web Developer, Univar, Chemical Distribution Company REDMOND, WASHINGTON - 2013

Programmed a JSON REST API with complete Jasmine test coverage for the PestWeb mobile app.

Founder, BitMojo, Web Site Development and Hosting Company OREGON AND WASHINGTON - 2001 - 2012

 Projects included building custom online registration systems for events sponsored by nationally recognized brands such as Subaru, Nautica, Merrill, Timberland, Balance Bar, and Men's Health. Responsible for full-stack development and hosting. Took online registrations for one client from zero to over \$2M per year.

Web Developer, Summit Projects, Interactive Agency HOOD RIVER, OREGON - 1999 - 2000

Used JavaScript in site navigation for www.nikeinc.com and content for www.swissarmy.com.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Willamette University, Salem, OR – 1992 Cumulative/major GPA: 3.6/3.9

Master of Fine Arts, Film, Video and Computer Animation University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA – 1995

Certificate in Ruby Programming University of Washington, Seattle, WA – 2013

MongoDB for Node.js Developers, Certificate of Completion MongoDB University – 2015